Guide to the Poles in Western Pennsylvania Collection, 1910s-1990s AIS.1965.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Poles in the United States and Western Pennsylvania, I.
  - Polish Communities Beyond Pittsburgh, 1608-1994; 1964-1977; 8.
    This subseries contains documents about Polish-American communities excluding Pittsburgh. This includes Allegheny County, Western Pennsylvania, and other states. Most Polish immigrants settled in New York, Pennsylvania, Michigan, Illinois, and Ohio. These states still have large Polish-American communities. Other states which have sizable Polish-American communities are Wisconsin, Florida, and Texas. Most of the documents in this subseries are about the Polish-American communities in Western Pennsylvania, but there are also documents about the Polish-American communities in Texas, Florida, and Pennsylvania as a whole. Most of the documetns are general information about the Polish-American community, but there are also specific records of United States Army service members. Included is the service record of Sergeant John F. Czajka (1893 - 1917) of Wisconsin who served in the First World War. Also included is information on General Josef Karge (1823 - 1892) who served during the American Civil War and Lieutenant General Matt Urban (1919 - 1995) who served in the Second World War. There is also an article on Polish women in America in the nineteenth century. There is also a guidebook for Repblican candidates with information about the Polish-American community in the United States distributed in 1960. Most of the documents in this subseries are in English with a few documents in Polish.
    - Candidate Information, pamphlet and card, 1964-1977 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Czajka, Jahn F., service record and book excerpt, 1890-1917 (Folder 67)
    - Essay, The Poles of Erie by Joseph Borkowski (Erie, PA), 1972 (Folder 68)
    - Guidebook for Republican Candidates re: Americans of Polish Origin, booklet, 1960 (Folder 69)
    - Handwritten notes by Joseph Borkowski, mostly about Polish pioneers in Western Pennsylvania, no date (Folder 70)
    - Hero of the War Between the States General Josef Karge, article, 1973 (Folder 71)
    - Historical Survey Responses from Polish Churches in Western Pennsylvania, parishes founded 1899 – 1924, survey, no date (Folder 72)
    - Jamestown Poles, Commemoration of Enfranchisement, Congressional Record (Pittsburgh), June 26, 1984 (Folder 73)
    - Lieutenant Colonel Matt Urban, retired, information about book, "The Matt Urban Story" (Michigan), no date (Folder 74)
    - List of Names, various national origins, no date (Folder 75)
    - New Florida Group Champions Fine Arts, (American Institute of American Culture, Inc.), journal article (Washington, DC), 1975 (Folder 76)
    - Poles in Michigan vol. 1, book (Detroit, MI), 1953 (Folder 77)
    - Poles in the History of Texas, article, Zgoda, (Texas), September 1, 1968 (Folder 78)
    - Polish American Association of Harrisburg, Inc., newsletter and Anniversary Booklet (Harrisburg, PA), 1994 (Folder 79)
    - Polish Americans and the U.S.A., booklet, 1608-1976 (Folder 80)
    - Polish Calendar, yearbooks, (Erie, PA and Doylestown, PA), 1941 and 1973 (Folder 81)
    - Polish History in Detroit, booklet (Detroit, MI), 1951 (Folder 82)
    - Polish People Helped Settle Erie, newspaper article, The Erie, PA Sunday Times, (Erie, PA), no date (Folder 83)
    - Polish Women who Helped Build America, article, Polish-American Journal, August 1974 (Folder 84)
    - Polish-American Chronicle, timeline, by Dr. Eugene Kusieliwicz, c. 1963 (Folder 85)
    - Ralf Madjelki, article in Pennsylvania Heritage (Harrisburg, PA), 1985 (Folder 86)
    - The Polish Heritage and The Future of Chicago, address by Lagodzinska at the University of Chicago, (Chicago, IL), November 23, 1953 (Folder 87)
- Societies, II.
  - Alliance of Poles of America, 1970-1978; 1. (Box 3)
    - 31st Convention- Akron, OH, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 32nd Convention, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 33rd Convention- Alliance of Poles Auditorium, Cleveland, OH, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 34th Convention- Toledo, OH, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Polish Lancers Society (Alliance of Poles Group 19)- Grand Opening, New Kensington, PA, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Alliance of Poles Finances, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Arsenal Board of Trade, 1968-1977; 2. (Box 3)
    - Lawrenceville Business List (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - July 4th Celebrations (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - City of Pittsburgh to ABT 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Congress to ABT 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - IRS to ABT 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Post Office to ABT 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - City of Pittsburgh to ABT 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - County of Allegheny to ABT 1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Arsenal Board of Trade Correspondence Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs, 1968-1986; 3. (Box 3)
    - "Our Quarter Century Polish Heritage" - History, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 20th Annual Convention- Pittsburgh, PA, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 38th Convention- Alliance College, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Kujawiaki Dancers Program- Alliance College, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Central Council of Polish Organizations, 1949-1990; 4. (Box 4)
    - Mlody Teatr (Young Theater), Filaret Club presents Enchanted Island- Hamtramck, MI, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - CCPO Correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Roll Book, 1957-1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Roll Book, 1967-1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Polish Day Dinner ticket (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Stamps (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Polonia News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - CCPO 50th Anniversary- William Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - CCPO 60th Anniversary- Duquesne University Chapel and Student Union Ballroom, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - CCPO Ustawy and Reguly, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Photo of CCPO President (1949, 1953, 1958, 1966, 1998) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - CCPO History by Borkowski (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - CCPO President's Report and Correspondence on Holocaust Exhibit with PAC, United Jewish Federation of Greater Pittsburgh, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - CCPO Annual Report, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - CCPO Finances (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - CCPO Ustawy and Reguly, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - CCPO Pittsburgh to Priests, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - CCPO Rules and Regulationss of Pittsburgh and Vicinity (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - CCPO News Releases (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Catholic League for Religious Assistance to Poland, 5.
    - 5th Biennial Convention- Wiloiam Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - West View Park, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Arsenal Family and Children's Center, Holy Family Institute, Polish Arts League of Pittsburgh, 6.
    - Arsenal Family and Children's Center Handbook, Pittsburgh, PA, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Holy Family Institute- Diamond Jubilee, Emsworth, PA, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Polish Arts League of Pittsburgh, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Kosciuszko Foundation, 7.
    - "Night in Old Krakow"- NYC, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Kosciuszko FOundation Ball- "A Night in the Tatras"- Grotto Grand Ballroom Suite, Pittsburgh, PA, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - 6th Annual Luncheon- John G. Brosky honored, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Kosciuszko Foundation Welcomes John E. Gore, in cooperation with the Polish Room Committee at University of Pittsburgh, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Outsanding Polonian Luncheon (Merle Addams)- Pittsburgh, PA, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Polish Falcons of America, 1959-1984; 8. (Box 5)
    - Johnstown Nest (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings- 90th Anniversary, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - PFA History (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - PFA Constitutions: Pittsburgh Nests (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - List of Pennsylvania Nests (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Nest 8- South Side, Pittsburgh, PA (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Nest 118- Pittsburgh Falconettes (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - PFA Falconettes (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Nest 52- Rochester, NY (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Nest 80- South Bend, IN (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Nest 141- Cleveland, OH (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Nest 146- New Castle, PA (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Nest 147- Mount Pleasant, PA (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Nest 176- Lawrenceville, Pittsburgh, PA (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Nest 182- Ambridge, PA (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Nest 260- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Nest 490- Braddock, PA (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Nest 607- Broughton, PA (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - District IV 37th Convention- Pittsburgh, PA, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - District IV 39th Convention- Nest 123, Erie, PA, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - District IV 41st Convention- Nest 182, Ambridge, PA, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - District IV 43rd Convention- Nest 147, Mount Pleasant, PA, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - District IV 44th Convention- South Side, Pittsurgh, PA, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - District IV 45th Convention- South Side, Pittsburgh, PA, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - District IV 46th Convention- South Side, Pittsburgh, PA, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - District IV 48th Convention- Nest 15, Braddock PA, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - District IV 49th Convention- Nest 118, Pittsburgh, PA, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - District IV 50th Convention- Nest 176, Holy Family CHurch Hall, Pittsburgh, PA, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - PFA District IV Reports and Finances (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - District XIII- Detroit, MI (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - District IV Polish Falcon Day- West View Park, Pittburgh, PA (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 26th National Convention- Buffalo, NY, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 30th National Convention- South Bend, IN, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 31st National Convention- New Britain, CT, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 32nd National Convention- Pittsburgh, PA, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - 33rd National Convention- Dearborn, MI, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - 75th Diamond Jubilee- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 40th Anniversary- Pittsburgh, PA, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 100th Anniversary- Vista International Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Centennial Souvenir Program Book, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Sokolstwo Vol. 1, 1953 (Box 4, Oversize 41)
    - Sokolstwo Vol. 2, 1956 (Box 4, Oversize 42)
    - Sokolstwo Vol. 3, 1973 (Box 4, Oversize 43)
    - Sokolstwo Vol. 4, 1974 (Box 4, Oversize 44)
  - Polish American Congress, 1948-1987; 9. (Box 6)
    - Protokol- Broadwood Hotel Auditorium, Philadelphia, PA, 1948 (Box 4A, Folder 1)
    - Protokol- Hotel Raleigh, Washington, D.C., 1950 (Box 4A, Folder 2)
    - 40th Anniversary- Conrad Hilton Hotel, Chicago, IL, 1984 (Box 4A, Folder 3)
    - 50th Anniversary- Group 841, Monaca, PA, 1994 (Box 4A, Folder 4)
    - Sprawozdanie (Reports)- Philadelphia, PA, 1948 (Box 4A, Folder 5)
    - Sprawozdanie (Reports)- Atlantic City, NJ, 1952 (Box 4A, Folder 6)
    - Sprawozdanie (Reports)- Chicago, IL, 1960 (Box 4A, Folder 7)
    - Sprawozdanie (Reports)_____- IL (Box 4A, Folder 8)
    - PAC Newsletter (Box 4A, Folder 9)
    - Poland's Millennium Celebration- Soldiers and Sailors Memorial Hall, 1966 (Box 4A, Folder 10)
    - Pulaski-Gabreski Day- William Penn Hotel, 1952 (Box 4A, Folder 11)
    - Pulaski Day- Hotel Fort Pitt, Pittsburgh, PA, 1954 (Box 4A, Folder 12)
    - Pulaski Day- Hotel William Penn, Pittsburgh, PA, 1955 (Box 4A, Folder 13)
    - Pulaski Day-Polish Falcons Hall, Braddock, PA, 1959 (Box 4A, Folder 14)
    - Pulaski Day- Hotel Penn Sheraton (William Penn), Pittsburgh, PA, 1960 (Box 4A, Folder 15)
    - Pulaski Day- Polish Falcons Hall, S 18th St., Pittsburgh, PA, 1964 (Box 4A, Folder 16)
    - Pulaski Day- William Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1969 (Box 4A, Folder 17)
    - Pulaski Day- St. Leocadia Social hall, Wilmerding, PA, 1975 (Box 4A, Folder 18)
    - Pulaski Day- Polish Falcon Hall, S 18th St., Pittsburgh, PA, 1976 (Box 4A, Folder 19)
    - Pulaski Day- Veterans memorial Hall, Butler St., Pittsburgh, PA, 1978 (Box 4A, Folder 20)
    - Pulaski Day- William Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1979 (Box 4A, Folder 21)
    - Pulaski Day- Bates St., Lasek's Restaurant, Pittsburgh, PA, 1982 (Box 4A, Folder 22)
    - Pulaski Day- Bates St., Lasek's Restaurant, Pittsburgh, PA, 1983 (Box 4A, Folder 23)
    - Pulaski Day- Bates St., Lasek's Restaurant, Pittsburgh, PA, 1984 (Box 4A, Folder 24)
    - Pulaski Day- Polish Army Veterans Post 41, Memorial Hall, Pittsburgh, PA, 1987 (Box 4A, Folder 25)
    - Polish Worker Solidarity (Box 4A, Folder 26)
    - PAC Press Clippings from Belgium, Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Latin America, Portugal, Spain (Box 4A, Folder 27)
    - PAC Press Clippings Vol. 2, 1948-1952 (Box 4A, Folder 28)
    - PAC Press Clippings Vol. 3, 1952-1954 (Box 4A, Folder 29)
  - Polish National Alliance, 10.
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1969, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Promien: Youth Leaders Magazine, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 75th Anniversary- District VIII, Hotel William Penn, Pittsburgh, PA, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 100th Anniversary Post Cards, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 100th Anniversary 1980- District VIII, Harmarville, PA, 1080 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Group 165- Beaver County, PA (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Group 165- Houston, TX (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Group 205- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Groups 146, 113, 507 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Groups 490, 352, unnamed nests (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Group 742- Derby, CT (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Group 832- Johnstown, PA (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Pulaski Societies (Groups 1052, 1243) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Group 2125- Johnstown, PA (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - PNA History (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - PNA District 8 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Polish Band- United Choirs, 11.
    - Polish Band- United Choirs (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia, 12.
    - Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Polonia Song and Dance Ensemble- Ambridge, PA, 13.
    - Polonia Song and Dance Ensemble (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - United Polish Societies, 14.
    - United Polish Societies- 25th Anniversary- Ambridge, PA, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Polish Roman Catholic Union, 1941-1970; 15.
    - 43rd National Convention- Baltimore, MD, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 44th National Convention 1946- Chicago, IL (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 46th Quadrennial Convention- Hotel William Penn, Pittsburgh, PA, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 85th Anniversary, 47th Quadrennial Convention- Detroit, MI, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 48th National Convention- Baltimore, MD, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 50th Quadrennial Convention- New Haven, CT, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 53rd National Convention- Cleveland, OH (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Women's Department (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Society of Our Lady of Czestochowa, Lodge 343- 42nd St., Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence to Joseph Borkowski, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Society of St. Michael the Archangel, Group 621- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Society of St. Gertrude, Group 1020- pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - 5th Annual National Basketball Tournament- Steubenville, OH, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - St. Casimir's Lodge, Group 531- Johnstown, PA (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - St. Elizabeth's Society, Group 535, Golden Anniversary- Lasek's Lodge, Bates St., Oakland, PA, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Group 1056- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Narod Polski, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - 25th Annual National Ten Pin Bowling Tournament- St. Casimir's Society, Group 237, Harmarville, PA, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Weteran, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Polish Women's Alliance, 1934-1979; 16.
    - Pamietnik- Pittsburgh, PA, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - 21st National Convention- William Penn, Pittsburgh, PA, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - 23rd Convention- Baltimore, MD, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - 26th Convention- Hartford, CT, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - 27th Quadrennial National Convention- WIlliam Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - 28th Convention- Dearborn, MI, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Golden Jubilee, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Photo Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - 15th Anniversary- Hotel Fort Pitt, Pittsburgh, PA, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - 35 Year Anniversary- Hotel William Penn, Pittsburgh, PA, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - 40th Anniversary, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - 60 Year Anniversary- Doylestown, PA, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Testimonial Banquet- Pittsburgh Hilton Hotel, Pittsburgh, PA, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Group 214- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Group 221- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Group 224- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Group 336- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Group 338 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Group 365- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Group 526- Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Honorata Wolowska News Clippings (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - 50th Anniversary Group 352- Holy Family Church, Lawrenceville, PA (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Diamond Jubilee- Chicago, IL, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - 5th Frontier Infantry Division, 17.
    - 5th Frontier Infantry Division (Box 6A, Folder 1)
  - St. Valentine Society of Pittsburgh, PA, 18.
    - Golden Jubilee, 1946 (Box 6A, Folder 2)
    - Finances, 1914-1974 (Box 6A, Folder 3)
  - Polish-American Club of Miami, 19.
    - 15th Anniversary Banquet and Ball- Police Benevolent Association, N.W. 14th St., Pittsburgh, PA (Box 6A, Folder 4)
  - Union of St. Joseph, 1950-1966; 20.; 0 box
    - Protokol- Pittsburgh, PA, 1933 (Box 6A, Folder 5)
    - Protokol- Pittsburgh, PA, 1946 (Box 6A, Folder 6)
    - Protokol- Pittsburgh, PA, 1950 (Box 6A, Folder 7)
    - Protokol- Pittsburgh, PA, 1966 (Box 6A, Folder 8)
    - Protokol 32nd Convention- New Kensington, PA, 1938 (Box 6A, Folder 9)
    - Zwiazkowiec Newspaper, 1954-1974 (Box 6A, Folder 10)
    - 13th Convention-Jeannette, PA, 1942 (Box 6A, Folder 11)
    - Convention- FIlaretic Hall, Wilmerding, PA, 1946 (Box 6A, Folder 12)
    - Constitution, 1940 (Box 6A, Folder 13)
    - Women's Department Banquet- Pittsburgh, PA, 1939 (Box 6A, Folder 14)
    - St. Edward Society (group 55 St. Joseph's Union)- Undated (Box 6A, Folder 15)
    - St. Ann's Society (Group 65 St. Joseph's Union)- Silver Jubilee, St. John's Hall, Rankin, PA, 1954 (Box 6A, Folder 16)
    - Society of Our Lady of Consolation (Group 43 St. Joseph's Union)- 40th Anniversary, Filaretic Hall, WIlmerding, PA, 1954 (Box 6A, Folder 17)
    - Golden Jubilee- West Penn Recreation center, Pittsburgh, PA, 1940 (Box 6A, Folder 18)
    - Golden Jubilee- New Kensington, PA, 1950 (Box 6A, Folder 19)
    - 22nd Convention- New Kensington, PA (Box 6A, Folder 20)
    - 23rd Convention- Jeannette, PA, 1942 (Box 6A, Folder 21)
    - 28th Convention- Lancer's Hall, New Kensington, PA (Box 6A, Folder 22)
  - Polish Army Veterans Association, 1931-1950; 21.
    - Congress- Pittsburgh, PA, 1931
    - Johnstown, PA
    - 30th, 35th, 40th, 45th, 50th Anniversary- Pittsburgh, PA
    - Post 41
    - Post 16, Ladies Auxiliary- Pittsburgh, PA
    - District III Silver Jubilee- Pittsburgh, PA, 1950
- Individuals, IV.
  - John Alexandrowicz, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Dora Alska (Alski)*, 1962-1975 (Folder 14)
  - Tadeusz Andrzejewski, 1966-1973 (Folder 15)
  - John G. Brosky*, 1979-1986 (Folder 16)
  - Capt. Robert Adolph Chodasiewicz, undated (Folder 17)
  - Arcybiskupa Jana Cieplaka, undated (Folder 18a)
  - Nicolaus Copernicus (Folder 18b)
  - Maria Sklodowska Curie, 1968-1969 (Folder 19)
  - Maria Dabrowska, undated (Folder 20)
  - Joseph B. Dobbs, 1960 (Folder 20A)
  - Stanley Dobrowolski (See 77: Blair Gunther)
  - John Dolegowski, undated (Folder 20B)
  - Rev. M.W. Drelak, 1962 (Folder 20C)
  - Ed Dybicz, 1962-1975 (Folder 21)
  - Dr. WM. Fronczek, 1982 (Folder 22)
  - Joseph Gorski, 1979 (Folder 23)
  - Col. Francis S. Gabreski, undated (Folder 24)
  - Rev. James Henry Gilmore, 1953 (Folder 25)
  - Col. Arthur Grabowski, 1885 (Folder 26)
  - Rev. Fr. Stanislaus J. Grabowski, 1975 (Folder 27)
  - Stephen S. Grabowski, undated (Folder 28)
  - Blair Gunther, 1935-1948 (Folder 29)
  - Franciszek Hodur, undated (Folder 30)
  - Chester J. Jakowski., 1995 (Folder 31)
  - Rev. John M. Jendzura*, 1972-1987 (Folder 32)
  - John Kane*, 1948 (Folder 33)
  - Gen. Joseph Karge*, 1963-1964 (Folder 34)
  - John C. Kluczynski, 1970 (Folder 35)
  - Maximilian Kolbe, 1973 (Folder 36)
  - Tadeusz Kosciuszko, 1967-1976 (Folder 37)
  - Rembert Kowalski, 1971 (Folder 38)
  - John Cardinal Krol (Folder 39)
  - Kardynal Krol, 1972 (Folder 40)
  - Rev. Msgr. Stanislaus R. Labujewski, 1971 (Folder 40A)
  - Haniel Long, 1974 (Folder 41)
  - John Malinovsky, 1922-1941 (Folder 42)
  - Edward C. Maliszewski, 1970-1995 (Folder 43)
  - Martin S. Luczkiewicz, 1973 (Folder 44)
  - Adam Mickiewicz, 1955 (Folder 45)
  - Stephen Mizwa, 1971 (Folder 46)
  - Helen Modjeska, 1878-1969 (Folder 47)
  - Donald F. Mushalko, 1969 (Folder 47A)
  - Rev. Stanislaus Parzyk, 1977 (Folder 48)
  - Fr. Marcel Pasiecznik, 1987 (Folder 48A)
  - Ignace Han Paderewski, 1939-1973 (Folder 49)
  - Rev. Paul E. Pindel, 1976 (Folder 50)
  - Casimir Pulaski*, 1941-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Casimir Pulaski, 1944-1975 (Folder 2)
  - John H. Radzyminski, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Dr. Louis Radzinski, 1963 (Folder 4)
  - Stanley J. Redmerski, 1983 (Folder 5)
  - Bernard B. Rogalski, 1985 (Folder 6)
  - Rev. Marion A. Rosenthal, 1958 (Folder 6A)
  - Stella Rybacki, 1954-1975 (Folder 7)
  - Piotra Sabatelli, undated (Folder 8)
  - Anthony Sadowsky, 1728-1982 (Folder 9)
  - Haym Solomon, 1973 (Folder 10)
  - Albin P. Schoepf, 1863-1971 (Folder 11)
  - Marcella Sembrich, 1900-1976 (Folder 12)
  - John M. Shalikashvili*, 1994 (Folder 13)
  - Rev. Msgr. Jacob C. Shinar, 1966 (Folder 13A)
  - Gen. Wladyslaw Sikorski, 1942 (Folder 14)
  - Marshal Edward Smigly-Rydz*, undated (Folder 15)
  - Lt. Col. George O. Sokalski, 1964 (Folder 16)
  - Major Henryk Sucharski, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Jan Srednicki*, 1904 (Folder 18)
  - Col. Dr. Teofil Starzynski, undated (Folder 19)
  - Jan Stobnicza, 1896-1959 (Folder 20)
  - Michael E. Swersey, 1958 (Folder 20A)
  - Dr. Maria A.J. Swiecicka, 1973 (Folder 21)
  - John R.B. Szala, 1971-1973 (Folder 22)
  - Fr. Zygmunt Szarnicki, 1981 (Folder 23)
  - Charles Trcziyulny*, 1964-1966 (Folder 24)
  - Slawek Walesa, 1988 (Folder 24A)
  - Mieczyslaw J. Wasilewski, 1975 (Folder 25)
  - Anthony Wayne, 1974-1975 (Folder 26)
  - John P. Wisniewski, 1973-1988 (Folder 27)
  - John Wojciechowski*, 1900-1936 (Folder 28)
  - Rev. Miroslaus Anthony Wojcicki, 1987 (Folder 28A)
  - Karol Cardinal Wojtyla, 1968-1993 (Folder 29)
  - Rev. John J. Wright, 1959 (Folder 30)
  - Lawrence R. Wujcikowski, 1995 (Folder 31)
  - Stefan Cardinal Wyszynski, 1973 (Folder 32)
  - Abraham O. Zabriskie, 1975 (Folder 33)
  - Stanley J. Zaremba*, 1943 (Folder 34)
- Wars and Polish Veterans, V.
  - Joseph Borkowski's Veteran's of Foreign Wars; Civil War; American Air Force Veterans; Polish Russian War of 1919 - 1920; Bicentennial Celebrations (Box 10)
  - Borkowski, Joseph, III.